jagrukbharat.com 2016-06-28

# Privacy Policy - Jagruk Bharat

This policy was prepared by the Foundation for Young Australians and International users ( **we** ,  **us** ** ** or ** ** **our** ).  It explains:

  * the  **kinds**  of personal information that we collect and hold;
  * **how  **we collect and hold that personal information;
  * the  **purposes**  for which we collect, hold, use and disclose that personal information.
  * **who  **we usually disclose that personal information to;
  * the  **overseas recipients**  we are likely to disclose that personal information to and the countries they are likely to be located in;
  * how you may  **access**  the personal information we hold about you and seek to  **correct**  that information; and
  * how you may  **complain**  to us about a breach of your privacy and how we will deal with such a complaint.

We aim to be open and transparent in all our dealings with young people.  If you have any questions about this policy or feedback on how we might improve it, please contact us.  This policy applies to all websites and social media profiles operated by us.  For a full list read our general terms and conditions.

All visitors to www.jagrukbharat.com (Website) are advised to read and understand our Privacy Policy carefully, as by accessing the Website you agree to be bound by the terms and conditions of the Privacy Policy and consent to the collection, storage and use of information relating to you as provided herein.

If you do not agree with the terms and conditions of our Privacy Policy, including in relation to the manner of collection or use of your information, please do not use or access the Website.

If you have any questions or concerns regarding this privacy policy, you should contact our Customer Support Desk at support@jagrukbharat.com

**Overview**  
We commit to respecting your online privacy data. We further recognize your need for appropriate protection and management of any personally identifiable information (“Personal Information“) you share with us. Information that is considered personal about you by us includes, but is not limited to, your name, address, email address or other contact information.

Presently, the use of this Website does not require You to register, however you may be required to register in the future.

You may register yourself by providing the following information which includes, but is not limited to:

Name;  
E-mail address;  
This privacy policy also applies to data we collect from users who are not registered as members of this site, including, but not limited to, browsing behavior, pages viewed etc.

Notification of Modifications and Changes to the T&C and Privacy Policy  
We reserve the right to change the Terms and Privacy Policy from time to time as we deem fit, without any intimation to you, and your continued use of the site will signify your acceptance of any amendment to these terms.

You are therefore advised to re-read the Terms of Service on a regular basis. Should it be that you do not accept any of the modifications or amendments to the Terms, you may terminate your use of this website immediately.

Information We Collect  
Information directly obtained from you:  
Our Website gives you an option of giving us contact information (like name, address, e-mail and telephone number) for the purposes of creating a profile on Our Website.

Any communication between you and the website, along with queries and posts on our website are also included in this. Certain information, such as your name, e-mail addresses, is collected in order to, among other things; verify your identity, use as account numbers in our record system and to provide information for the leads generated.

**Information collected indirectly:**  
Certain information about you is collected automatically when you visit our website. This includes your IP address, browser type and operating system, your immediate Internet history, information collected through cookies (more information on this below), etc.

We may also obtain information relating to you from third party sources such as social networking websites, databases, online marketing firms, etc. We collect only basic information such as name, e-mail address, contact number, location etc.

We also collect and store personal information provided by you from time to time on the Site. We only collect and use such information from you that we consider necessary for achieving a seamless, efficient and safe experience, customized to your needs including:

To enable the provision of services opted for by you;  
To send the latest newsletters to you; and  
To comply with applicable laws, rules and regulations  
Where any service requested by you involves a third party, such information as is reasonably necessary by the JB to carry out your service request may be shared with such third party.

To the extent possible, we provide you the option of not divulging any specific information that you wish for us not to collect, store or use. You may also choose not to use a particular service or feature on the Site, and opt out of any non-essential communications from the Jagrukbharat.

Further, transacting over the internet has inherent risks which can only be avoided by you following security practices yourself such as ensuring that Your e-mail address and profile information is confidential. Any information sent to Us by Your e-mail address which has not been sent by You should be notified to our customer care team at the earliest.

**How Information Is Collected**  
Before or at the time of collecting personal information, we will identify the purposes for which information is being collected.  
We will collect and use of personal information solely with the objective of fulfilling those purposes specified by us and for other compatible purposes, unless we obtain the consent of the individual concerned or as required by law.  
We will only retain personal information as long as necessary for the fulfillment of those purposes.  
We will collect personal information by lawful and fair means and, where appropriate, with the knowledge or consent of the individual concerned.  
Personal data should be relevant to the purposes for which it is to be used, and, to the extent necessary for those purposes, should be accurate, complete, and up-to-date.

**Cookies**  
We use data collection devices such as “cookies” on certain pages of our Websites. “Cookies” are small files sited on your hard drive that assist us in providing customized services. We also offer certain features that are only available through the use of a “cookie”. Cookies can also help us provide information, which is targeted to your interests. Cookies may be used to identify logged in or registered users.  
Third party vendors including www.google.com (“Google”) may use cookies to serve ads based on your visits to this Website. You may visit the website of the third party and choose to opt out of the use of cookies for interest-based advertising, if the third party offers such an option. You may choose to opt-out of the DoubleClick cookie that Google and its partners use for interest-based advertising by visiting Ads Settings. (Alternatively, you can direct users to opt out of a third-party vendor’s use of cookies for interest based advertising by visiting aboutads.info.)  
The website also has enabled the Google Analytics Advertising, which allows Google to collect data about users on our website, in addition to Google advertising cookies and anonymous identifiers. You may choose to opt out of this by downloading and installing the Google Analytics opt-out add-on here https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/.

**External Links on Website**  
The Website may include hyperlinks to other web sites or content or resources. We have no control over any websites or resources, which are provided by companies or persons other than Us.

You acknowledge and agree that We are not responsible for the availability of any such external sites or resources, and does not endorse any advertising, products or other materials on or available from such websites or resources.

You acknowledge and agree that We are not liable for any loss or damage which may be incurred by you as a result of the availability of those external sites or resources, or as a result of any reliance placed by you on the completeness, accuracy or existence of any advertising, products or other materials on, or available from, such websites or resources. These third-party service providers and Third-Party Sites may have their own privacy policies governing the storage and retention of your personal information that you may be subject to. We recommend that when you enter a Third-Party Site, you review the Third Party Site’s privacy policy as it relates to safeguarding your personal information. We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit the Website.

**Our Use of Your Information**  
Your contact information is also used to contact you when necessary. We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our Website. Your IP address is also used to help identify you and to gather broad demographic information. Finally, we may use your IP address to help protect our partners and ourselves from fraud. We will continue to enhance our security procedures as new technology becomes available. We will transfer information about you if We are acquired by or merged with another JB. In this event, we will notify you by email or by putting a prominent notice on the site before information about you is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy.

We may release your personal information to a third-party in order to comply with a Court Order or other similar legal procedure, or when we believe in good faith that such disclosure is necessary to comply with the law; prevent imminent physical harm or financial loss; or investigate or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, or violations of Our Terms of Use. We may disclose personally identifiable information to parties in compliance with our Copyright Policy as mentioned in the Terms of Use as we in our sole discretion believe necessary or appropriate in connection with an investigation of fraud, intellectual property infringement, piracy, or other unlawful activity. In such events, We may disclose name, address, country, phone number, email address and Jagrukbharat name.

**Confidentiality**  
You further acknowledge that the Website may contain information which is designated confidential by Us and that you shall not disclose such information without our prior written consent.

Your information is regarded as confidential and therefore will not be divulged to any third party, unless if legally required to do so to the appropriate authorities.

We will not sell, share, or rent your personal information to any third party or use your e-mail address for unsolicited mail. Any emails sent by us will only be in connection with the provision of agreed services and products.

**Our Disclosure of Your Information**  
Due to the existing regulatory environment, we cannot ensure that all of your private communications and other personally identifiable information will never be disclosed in ways not otherwise described in this Privacy Policy. By way of example (without limiting and foregoing), we may be forced to disclose information to the government, law enforcement agencies or third parties. Under certain circumstances, third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications, or members may abuse or misuse your information that they collect from our Website. Therefore, although we use industry standard practices to protect your privacy, we do not promise, and you should not expect, that your personally identifiable information or private communications would always remain private.

As a matter of policy, we do not sell or rent any personally identifiable information about you to any third party. However, the following describes some of the ways that your personally identifiable information may be disclosed:

**External Service Providers** : There may be a number of services offered by external service providers that help you use our Websites. If you choose to use these optional services, and in the course of doing so, disclose information to the external service providers, and/or grant them permission to collect information about you, then their use of your information is governed by their private policy.  
**Other Corporate Entities** : We share much of our data, including personally identifiable information about you, with our parent and/or subsidiaries that are committed to serving your online needs and related services, throughout the world. Such data will be shared for the sole purpose of enhancing your browsing experience and providing our services to you. To the extent that these entities have access to your information, they will treat it at least as protectively as they treat information they obtain from their other members. It is possible that We and/or its subsidiaries, or any combination of such, could merge with or be acquired by another business entity. Should such a combination occur, you should expect that we would share some or all of your information in order to continue to provide the service. You will receive notice of such event (to the extent that it occurs).

**Law and Order:  **We cooperate with law enforcement inquiries, as well as other third parties to enforce laws, such as: intellectual property rights, fraud and other rights. We can (and you authorize us to) disclose any information about you to law enforcement and other government officials as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate, in connection with an investigation of fraud, intellectual property infringements, or other activity that is illegal or may expose us or you to legal liability.  
Accessing and Reviewing Information  
Following registration, you can review and change the information you submitted each time except your display name. If you change any information we may keep track of your old information. You can change your registration information such as: name, address, city, state, zip code, country, phone number, and profile.

We will retain in our files information you have requested to remove for certain circumstances, such as to resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems and enforce our terms and conditions. Further, such prior information is never completely removed from our databases due to technical and legal constraints, including stored ‘back up’ systems. Therefore, you should not expect that all of your personally identifiable information will be completely removed from our databases in response to your requests.

**Other Information Collectors**  
Except as otherwise expressly included in this Privacy Policy, this document only addresses the use and disclosure of information we collect from you. To the extent that you disclose your information to other parties, whether they are on our Websites or on other sites throughout the Internet, different rules may apply to their use or disclosure of the information you disclose to them. To the extent that we use third party advertisers, they adhere to their own privacy policies. Since we do not control the privacy policies of the third parties, you are subject to ask questions before you disclose your personal information to others.

**Security**  
We treat data as an asset that must be protected against loss and unauthorized access. We employ many different security techniques to protect such data from unauthorized access by members inside and outside the JB. We do not recommend transfer of sensitive information (such as credit card number) and bank account details via the Site to other Users. Users are recommended to do so offline, on the phone or via personal emails. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once We receive it. However, “perfect security” does not exist on the Internet. You therefore agree that any security breaches beyond the control of our standard security procedures are at your sole risk and discretion.

**Disclaimer**  
We cannot ensure that all of your private communications and other personal information will never be disclosed in ways not otherwise described in this Privacy Policy. Therefore, although we are committed to protecting your privacy, we do not promise, and you should not expect, that your personal information will always remain private. As a user of the Site, you understand and agree that you assume all responsibility and risk for your use of the Site, the internet generally, and the documents you post or access and for your conduct on and off the Site.

### **Modifications**

We may change this policy from time to time.  Any updated version will be posted on our website.  We encourage you to check in regularly to ensure you are aware of any updates.

### **How to contact us**

You can contact us:

  * by email: [privacy@jagrukbharat.com](mailto:privacy@jagrukbharat.com)
  * via the web: [contact-us](http://jagrukbharat.com/contact-us/)

© 2015 Jagrukbharat  ABN 40 702 899 574
